# Tyler La Fronz

lafronzt@gmail.com | +1 (908) 670-3094 | LaFronz.com | Marlboro, NJ

### **Executive Summary**

Throughout the past four years at Wentworth, I've come to learn about software development and programming, through its hands-on project-based learning. I've also come to learn about myself, and how I have a passion for helping others connect and build a better more connected world.

### Education

Wentworth Institute of Technology, Boston, MA

Aug. 2017

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, Dean's List - Summer 2016 & Spring 2017

**Skills** 

Languages: Java,Working Knowledge: Prolog,<br/>C/C++, AssemblySoftware: D3, Eclipse,<br/>Logisim, SQL Developer,<br/>Visual Studio, WireSharkSelf-taught:<br/>Twitter's Fabric,<br/>PuTTY, Git, Python

**Experience** 

ISO Developers, Winthrop, MA

Sept. 2016 - Dec. 2016

Software Developer Co-Op

- Developed Cross Platform Mobile Applications using the Ionic Platform, AngularJS, HTML, and CSS.
- Implemented Customer Product Ideas using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- Coded in groups using Git, and other version control systems.

## Applied Geographics, Inc., Boston, MA

Jan. 2016 – April 2016

Network Administrator Co-Op

- Implemented and supervised a RADIUS server for use in an 802.1X wireless network.
- Maintained and supported Website infrastructure.
- Coordinated Website Analytic Reporting.

# **Projects & Research**

Music Map (April 2017) - MusicMap.LaFronz.com

• Developed a Visualization of a Spotify user's library using D3, NodeJS, and Spotify's web API to create a new way for users to view their library items.

The Vault (Fall 2014)

• Designed, planned and implemented a command line Java based program that interacts with a SQL database for potential app implementation in a two-person team.

Battleship Prototype (Fall 2015) - Github.com/lafronzt/Battleship

• Built the board game Battleship into a 1-player game in Assembly Language while working with 2 others.

#### Leadership

### **Wentworth Student Government**

Sep. 2013 - Current

<u>President</u> – Elected by entire the student body to serve a 1-year term. Act as student liaison to Departments and Divisions. Preside over Weekly Meetings and create the agenda.

- Hosted regular Meetings with the Institute's President, Vice Presidents, and Associate Vice Presidents, to discuss ongoing and future campus and Student concerns.
- Advocated for more efficient ways to target events and engage underrepresented campus groups and commuters with Campus Administration.

<u>Academic Affairs Officer</u> - Elected by the student body to work closely with our campus partners on issues revolving around class schedules, class options, and academic problems and changes. Worked closely with the Provost and Registrar.

Wentworth Leadership Institute (Completed a 12-week Leadership seminar)

Mar. 2017

#### Wentworth Alliance

Aug. 2015 - Jan. 2017

• Ensure that a community at WIT has their needs meet and understood by administration, staff, and faculty.

## **Preferred Name Implementation**

Oct. 2015 - Present

- Implement a Preferred Name Policy across Wentworth's intranet to ensure that over 4000 students, faculty, and staff can use the name that they identify with the most.
- Communicate with other Student Leaders throughout the College of the Fenway consortium, a collective of 5 other Colleges and Universities in the Fenway area of Boston.

# **Appointments**

- Search Committees Registrar, Director of the Center for Diversity and Social Justice Programs
- Wentworth Alumni Association Student Board Member